# Malcolm Simmons

Professional Class A Trucker Driver

### Contact

**Address** 

Orlando, FL, 32803

**Phone** 

(407) 312-6447

E-mail

Malcolmx7892@yahoo.com

LinkedIn

www.linkedin.com/in /malcolm-simmons-5b5045207

**WWW** 

https://github.com /MalcolmSimmons789

#### **Skills**

Commercial driving

Route logs

GPS and route planning

Shipping and packaging

Specialty tools

Repair services

Installation planning

Diagnostic abilities

First Aid and CPR

Swim instruction

Organized Truck Driver with proven track record of delivering within specified time frames. Customer-focused and strong communicator with ability to effectively interact with others. Experienced Lifeguard versed in keen observation of swimmers and safety protocols. Offered valuable tips and instruction to patrons of various ages to build confidence and strength in water. Strong communicator and team player with superior work ethic.

## **Work History**

2019-05 -Current

#### **Truck Driver**

Swift Transportation, Orlando, Florida

- Completed regular inspections and maintenance actions, as well as basic equipment repairs, to keep equipment operating at peak levels.
- Dropped and hooked trailers and changed configuration of equipment when necessary.
- Finalized daily logs on schedule to update internal records and uphold DOT requirements.
- Managed supplier record tracking and data communications tasks while automating operations to enhance efficiency.

2018-09 -2019-03

#### **Deliver Driver**

Pizza Hut, Orlando, Florida

- Communicated customer complaints, requests and feedback to company management for swift resolution.
- Fostered positive working relationships with customers by responding to questions and concerns.
- Completed on-time deliveries by choosing best and most efficient routes.
- Completed rush deliveries on tight timetables to satisfy customer needs.

2017-10 -2018-07

#### **Installation Technician**

BrightHouse Networks, Orlando, Florida

- Followed all company guidelines regarding safety procedures when out in field.
- Maintained high level of safety when using hand and power equipment for hoisting, measuring,

#### Team Bonding

#### Strong communicator

testing and drilling of various types of installations.

- Commissioned staff members for specific projects and tasks, tracked activities and solved complex issues to enhance productivity.
- Completed timely project management within budget constraints on multi-faceted problems for executive leadership, while fostering meaningful relationships with contractors.
- Demonstrated equipment capabilities to customer and responded to questions and complaints.

# 2016-11 - Overnight Stocker

2017-08

2016-10

Walmart, Orlando, Florida

- Realigned merchandise throughout assigned section to give shelves and racks professional appeal.
- Readied items for sales floor stocking by affixing tags and preparing pallets.
- Performed light housekeeping and cleaning by discarding trash and cardboard and sweeping and mopping floors.
- Inspected floor displays, noted missing items and immediately replenished merchandise.

# 2014-06 - **Lifeguard**

Wet'n' Wild, Orlando, Florida

- Learned and maintained proficiency in first responder skills such as First Aid and CPR to offer individuals in distress optimal support.
- Observed weather and water conditions and alerted visitors to potential dangers, including storms and rip currents.
- Completed basic maintenance and repairs to keep pools functioning properly.
- Maximized customer satisfaction by greeting all pool patrons with courtesy and resolving any issues promptly and with positive attitude.

## **Education**

2015-08 - High School Diploma

2016-06 Orange Techinical College - Orlando, FL